https://www.antiquities.co.uk/privacy-policy/

OpenCloseAll AntiquitiesBy Category
WELCOME
How to find the perfect antiquity You can browse our stock by the type of artefact you’re interested in (view by Category) or by the civilisation it came from (view by Culture). Then filter and refine your search by material, metal, pottery type, shape, pattern, deities etc.
Genuine & certified All our items are genuine and come with a certificate of authenticity.
Something specific in mind? If you need further help, or for sourcing enquiries, please call us:
+44 (0)20 8364 4565
Gifts under £250
Roman Glass under £250Jewellery & Amulets under £250Ancient Weapons under £250
Gifts under £1000
Roman Glass under £1000Jewellery & Amulets under £1000Ancient Weapons under £1000
Rare & Fine Artefacts
New Items
Red Terracotta Oil Lamp in Custom-Made Case
$100.20
Holy Land Terracotta Oil Lamp in Custom-Made Case
$100.20
Selection of Anatolian Barbed Bronze Arrowheads
$40.08
Gandharan Buddha Statues
Shabtis (Ushabtis)
Tomb Attendants & Offerings
Fat Lady FigurinesMusician & Dancer FigurinesWarrior Figures
Terracotta Figurines
Greek Terracotta Figurines
Horse Figurines
Tang & Ming Dynasty Horses
Fertility FigurinesAppliqués & ProtomesFragments
View All Ancient Figurines >
Ancient Jewellery
Rings
Numismatic Books
British Coin BooksGreek Coin BooksRoman Coin BooksByzantine Coin Books
Antiquarian Books
View All Books >
Paper & Textiles
Ancient Textiles
Cartonnage & Mummy Masks
Manuscripts
View All Paper & Textiles >
By Culture
Learn More
Ancient Egyptian Shabtis and Funerary StatuettesCarnelian in Ancient Egyptian CultureWhat is Egyptian Faience?
View All Egyptian Antiquities >
View All Egyptian Articles >
The Roman Empire
Roman Antiquities
Ancient Roman CoinsAppliquesFragmentsGod & Goddess FigurinesWeapons & Tools
Roman Glass
All Roman GlassUnguentariaBalsamariaIrridescent GlassMoulded Glass
Roman Oil Lamps
Featuring
Bronze PatinaMarbleLion's HeadDionysian Context
Roman Jewellery
All Roman JewelleryRoman Gold RingsRoman Glass JewelleryRoman Glass NecklacesRoman Pendant EarringsRoman BroochesHighly Decorative PiecesPhallic Pendants
Roman Mythology
FaunusHerculesLunaMarsMinervaPutto (Cherub)Sol Invictus
Roman Emperors
Gordian III (& Tranquillina)Galba
Learn More
Mythology of Gemstones in Ancient JewelleryRoman Medicine and Medical Tools
Collecting Guides
Collecting Guide: Ancient Roman Glass
View All Roman Antiquities >
View All Roman Articles >
The Byzantine Empire
Byzantine Antiquities
Byzantine Oil LampsByzantine CoinsTrade Weights
Byzantine Jewellery
Learn More
Ancient Greek Votive Offerings in AntiquityThe Symposium in Classical CulturesDionysus: Madness, Release and WinePolychromy in Ancient Greece
Collecting Guides
Collecting Guide: Types of Ancient Greek Vase
View All Greek Antiquities >
View All Greek Articles >
Gandharan, Indian & Bactrian
Gandharan Antiquities
Buddhist StatuesFertility FigurinesHarpoons
Featuring
Buddha
Gandharan Ideology
Shakyamuni BuddhaBodhisattvaMaitreya
Learn More
The Influence of Greek Art on Gandharan StatuesGandharan Buddha Poses and Postures
View All Gandharan Antiquities >
View All Gandharan Articles >
Chinese & Oriental
Chinese Antiquities
Tang Fat LadiesChinese Pottery WarriorsMale Tomb AttendantsFemale Tomb AttendantsHorse FigurinesMeiping VasesPottery Jars
Shipwreck Pottery
Tek SingHoi AnBlue & White
Featuring
ChrysanthemumsLotus flowersLionsDogsBirds
Chinese Mythology
Dragon
Learn More
View All Oriental Antiquities >
By Region
Babylonian ArtefactsMesopotamian ArtefactsSumerian ArtefactsLevantine Artefacts
Learn More
Culture Focus: The Luristan EmpireThe Luristan Empire: Beauty of BronzeScythian Gold
View All Near Eastern Antiquities >
View All Near Eastern Articles >
Anglo Saxon & Viking
Saxon & Viking Antiquities
Belt BucklesBrooches & Dress Pins
Featuring
BronzeSilver
Learn More
Medieval Antiquities
Medieval JewelleryMedieval ManuscriptsMedieval SealsBook of HoursTools & Accessories
Featuring
GildingCrossesSaints
Christian Ideology
Agnus Dei (Lamb of God)ChristSt Catherine
Learn More
Illuminated Manuscripts & Vellum Pages
View All Medieval Antiquities >
View All Medieval Articles >
Collections
Chinese & Oriental
Chinese Art
The Horse in Chinese Art and CultureThe Fat Lady in Chinese Tang Art
Shipwreck Pottery
Ca Mau Shipwreck PotteryHoi An Shipwreck PotteryKangxi Blue & White Shipwreck PotteryTek Sing Shipwreck Pottery
Provenance Collections
Gandharan
The Professor Zahid Pervez Butt Collection
Bronze Age
The Desmond Morris CollectionThe Professor Dan Barag Commentary
Blog
Latest Articles
Religious Syncretisms in the Ancient Mediterranean Region
Egyptian Amulets and their Meanings
Animal Symbolism in Roman Art
Engraved Gemstones in Ancient Rome
Most Popular Articles
Egyptian Amulets and their Meanings
What We Do
Antiquities DealerNumismatic Coin DealerPremium Fossil DealerSource, Identify & Value
Buying an Antiquity
ProvenanceOur PhilosophyAuthenticityCurrent Antiquity Legislation
Meet The Team
Chris Martin
Anastasia Hanna
Francesca Puccetti
Expertise & Advisory Roles Ancient & Oriental is the website brand of Ancient Art – London’s leading purveyor of antiquities and coins for over 40 years. All items are sold with a certificate of authenticity.
Our founder, Chris Martin, actively helps to educate, value and protect ancient treasures:
Treasure Valuation Committee – Member
ADA Committee – Deputy Chairman
BNTA – Chairman
About Us >
Principal Staff >
ContactOrdering
How to OrderMy AccountMy Orders
Login$0.00
Home > Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy for Ancient & Oriental with C.J. Martin Coins and Ancient Art
This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.
What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?
When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information or other details to help you with your experience.
Information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website. This includes your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths.
Information you provide to us when registering with our website (your name and e-mail address) either when using the contact form or newsletter registration form.
Information that you provide to us when using the services on our website, or that is generated in the course of the use of those services.
Information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our us on.
When do we collect information?
We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site. We will also collect information from any correspondance including email and verbal.
When you purchase an object from our online gallery, as part of the buying and selling process we collect the personal information you provide us such as your name, address, telephone number and email address.
Any other personal information that you choose to send to us.
How do we use your information?
We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:
Administer our website and business.
Enable your use of the services available on our website.
Send statements, invoices and payment reminders to you and collect payments from you.
Send you non-marketing commercial communications.
Send you e-mail notifications that you specifically requested.
Send you marketing communications. This can include an e-mail newsletter, if you have subscribed. You can opt out of our newsletters at any time. This can also include promotional activity, such as sale events, discounts and invitations to events.
Keep our website secure and prevent fraud.
How do we protect your information?
Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.
We use regular Malware Scanning.
Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.
We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order to maintain the safety of your personal information.
All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.
How do we store personal information?
To the extent that we are required to do so by law, this is a minimum of 6 years.
If we believe that the documents may be relevant to any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings, disclosures required by law or court order, disclosures to the police, tax authorities or other public or government authorities.
In order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.
In order to provide information to our insurers.
To provide you with information (for instance, via newsletters) about goods or services we feel may interest you. We will contact you in this manner if you have consented to this expressly by opting in on our website or via e-mail. Interaction (clicks to view items detailed within newsletters) via our newsletters will constitute as consent prior to 25th May 2018. After this date, opt in participation will be required.
Personal information that we process for a purchase or informational purposes shall not be kept longer than is necessary for those purposes and is required by law.
We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.
You acknowledge that the transmission of information over the Internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the Internet.
This website is hosted by WordPress. WordPress may collect information on how users access the website by using tracking ID unique to each user through the use of cookies. The WordPress privacy policy can be found here.
The payment process and what data is used?
Payments by Worldpay
Payments via our website are made through a secure Worldpay server. No credit details are stored on Ancient & Oriental.
The details supplied and stored by Worldpay will be encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.
Ancient & Oriental is PCI compliant. A record of this certificate can be viewed on our site premises, Oakwood N14 4UW.
Payment by Paypal
By choosing PayPal to complete your purchase your credit card data is stored encrypted through the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI-DSS). Your purchase transaction data is kept only as long as necessary to complete your purchase transaction. After it is complete, your purchase transaction information is deleted. PayPal adheres to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands such as Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensures the secure handling of credit card information by our online gallery.
Do we use ‘cookies’?
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.
We use cookies to:
Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.
You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Since all browsers are a little different, look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.
If you turn cookies off, It won’t affect the user’s experience.
We use Google Analytics on our website. Google Analytics sets cookies in order to track your usage of the website. Google Analytics stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the USA. Google Analytics might also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. By using this website you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes stated above. More information on how Google uses data can be found here.
Disclosing personal information:
We will not, without your consent, supply your personal information to any third party for the purpose of their or any other third party’s direct marketing.
When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order and arrange shipment, this implies your consent that we can collect and use it for that specific reason only.
We may disclose your personal information to any of our employees, officers, insurers, professional advises, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this policy.
We may disclose your personal information to the extent that we are required by law and/or in connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings.
We may disclose your personal information in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for purposes of fraud prevention).
We may disclose your personal information in the event you violate our Terms and Conditions of sale.
Apart from the reasons stated in this policy, we will not provide your personal information to third parties.
Third-party disclosure
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.
However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.
Our website includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.
We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties.
Third parties may include but are not limited to: Courier services (Royal Mail, TNT, PARCELFORCE, FEDEX, DPD, UPS, POSTAGE SUPERMARKET), Insurance providers, Payment providers (Worldpay, Paypal)
Third-party links
We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website.
Google
Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.
Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.
We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.
We have implemented the following:
Remarketing with Google AdSense
DoubleClick Platform Integration
We, along with third-party vendors such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.
Opting out:
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.
We agree to the following:
Users can visit our site anonymously. Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.
You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes:
On our Privacy Policy Page
You can change your personal information:
By emailing us
By calling us
By logging in to your account
How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.
Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?
It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking
COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)
When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.
We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.
Do we let third-parties, including ad networks or plug-ins collect PII from children under 13?
Fair Information Practices
The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.
In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:
We will notify you via email
Within 30 business days
We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.
CAN SPAM Act
The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.
We collect your email address in order to:
Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions
Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.
Send you additional information related to your product and/or service
Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.
To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:
Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.
Unsubscribe from receiving future emails:
You can email us at ancient.art@btinternet.com and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.
Contacting Us
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.
W: antiquities.co.uk
A: The Gallery
Trent Park Equestrian Centre
Bramley Rd
London
N14 4UW
UK
Email: ancient.art@btinternet.com
Tel: 020 8364 4565
Last Edited on 2018-04-24
ShareClick to share on Facebook (Opens in new window)Click to share on Pinterest (Opens in new window)Click to share on Twitter (Opens in new window)Click to share on WhatsApp (Opens in new window)
By continuing to use the site, you agree to the use of cookies. more information AcceptThe cookie settings on this website are set to "allow cookies" to give you the best browsing experience possible. If you continue to use this website without changing your cookie settings or you click "Accept" below then you are consenting to this.Close
